BERTRAND DE MONTETY

ABOUT ME

Software engineer with 6 years of experience. I have developed professional proficiency in the France, United Arab Emirates and UK and in several industries: cybersecurity, embedded systems and finance. My quick adaptability to new environments, tools, and processes has enabled me to work collaboratively with diverse teams and to establish myself as a valuable contributor. While I'm proficient in a wide range of programming languages, my main areas of expertise are C++, Java, and Python.

EDUCATION

Master's in computer science, specialised in security, network and system, *EPITA*, *Paris* 2015 - 2017 Major courses: network, operating system, computer science, cybersecurity, forensic, cryptography, maths.

SKILLS

Languages C++, Java, Python, Bash, SQL with a solid foundation in JS, Perl.

Knowledge Finance, OS fundamentals, security & network, Linux, Git, Algo, System Design.

EXPERIENCE

Software engineer at Equiduct

London, UK

Now - Mars 2021

Software developer of a trading venue. My tasks were to give clients new trading opportunities, improve trading experience and maintain and upgrade the overall platform.

• Business projects:

Nordic expansion: creation of new order type for Liquidity Providers to mirror top offers on Nordic markets. Trade reporting: validating and publishing trade reports in compliance with MIFID II directives.

- Tech projects: Latency benchmark: upgrade latency monitoring system and reports.

 Service authentication: upgrade and modernise authentication service for the web applications using JWT.

 Other: creating client reports, maintenance of the platform, upgrade web component from JSP to RESTFUL.
- Components: Matching Engine, UIs, webapps, FIX client, DB.
- Technology stack used: C++, Java, Python, Perl, PL/SQL, MySQL, Bash, SVN.

Software engineer at Sagemcom

London, UK

Oct 2018 - Dec 2020

Software development of the middle-ware of an embedded system device and local technical support to the Youview's teams to create a new set-top box for our client, British Telecom (BT).

- **Development and integration**: of Sagemcom's software components in Youview's middleware (data collection, diagnostics app, power and software manager). Developed in C++ and C.
- Technical support: team representative providing help onsite for the client and partner companies, following all the technical topics (dev tasks, bugs, deliveries, demo, coordination testing), led calls, local UK support for Sagemcom project and pre-sales teams.
- Technology stack used: embedded system, C++, C, Bash, DBus, Linux, agile development tools, TR-069.

Software engineer at OTG

Abu Dhabi, UAE

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

C++ development forensic application, designed to facilitate large scale of network data investigations, by performing a deep analysis (DPI) and enrichment over these network data.

- Responsibilities: development, tests, coordination, deployment.
- **Deployment and support**: installation of the solution on the customers side and onsite support.
- Technology stack used: C++, C, Linux, Python, Bash, SQL.